Listen to a talk on environmental conservation.
Let's talk the environmental issue that has to do with how common household products have changed.
More and more products contain bacterial killing chemicals these days.
These antibacterial chemicals aren't just in product like soap.
They are in all sorts of household cleaners and toothpaste.
And if you think about it for second you will realize that most of those chemicals just end up going down the drain.
But you are probably thinking that all that stuff go through a treatment plan that removes chemicals, right?
After all that's what happens to stuff that goes down the drain Well,
waste water is treated, but that doesn't usually remove all the chemicals in it.
The chemicals left in the treated water get into the aquatic environment.
That is into the rivers, and streams where plants and fish and other animals live.
Now to find out the effect of antibacterial chemicals on freshwater ecosystems,
a study was done with algae, which are tiny plant-like organisms.
Different species of algae were taken to a lab
and then exposed to just a few antibacterial chemicals found in the streams. And guess what?
In the experiment, the overall growth of algae and the number of species dropped.
This is not good and here is why.
Algae are the base of the aquatic food chain
which means that other organisms depend on them for food.
So if the chemicals kill algae at the bottom of the food chain
the whole system is being disrupted.